William Temple Franklin Papers 1775-1819 Mss.B.F86
American Philosophical Society
- William Temple Franklin Papers, 1775-1790; Mss.B.F86; 4.5 lin. feet
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Februrary 11; ALS, 1p.; Jones, Ezra.
    Enclosed sends a "Catalogue of Characters"; offers to be bearer of any commands for America; sails in the "Luzerne" for Philadelphia; announces the arriaval of the "Caption Jones."
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Feb. 14; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Allaire, Peter
    Asks for a pass to Brussels.
    A. E. by W[illiam] T[emple] F[ranklin]. Asks if Dr. Franklin will grant this request. By [Benjamin Franklin]. "No."
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Feb. 15; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    The arrival of the "Confederacy"; is anxious for news of Congress; arrangements in the ports of France.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Feb. 19; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Introduces William Brush from one of the northern states, and Mr. Wilkinson of South Carolina.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Feb. 23; ALS, 1p.; J. Dubosi, Mlle
    Wishes to know if Madame Aves has written to him about the ring and pair of shoe buckles, she expected to send him from London.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Feb. 24; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Glad to know about the false report, that his uncle [John Williams] is in London; he is with him, and in proof sends a letter from him; begs that he destroy this report.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Feb. 24; ALS, 2p.; Williams, John
    Requests that the malicious report that he is in London, be denied; he has not been there since Oct. 6th, 1778.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Feb. 26; A. L. 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Sends a bill for acceptance.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Feb. 27; ALS, 2p.; Feutry, Aimé Ambroise Joseph
    Dedicates to him the second edition of his "Choix d'Histoire" and the third of his "Robinson"; encloses; a "Bouts-rimés" for Mlle. de Chaumont.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 2; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Asks the return of the letter from the Marquis Lafayette; thanks him for his zeal in pleading his cause; wishes to obtain the brevet of Lieutenant-Colonel to prove to America that his country was pleased with his conduct.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 3; ALS, 1p.; Lockyer, B
    Thanks him for his recommendation to the school, but decides to place his children near the sea-coast where they will have no opportunity of contracting the Parisian customs.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 10; ALS, 2p.; Caslon, William
    Consigned to Messrs. Fizeaux and Grand ninety-six pounds of two line Pica Doric for his grandfather; disappointed he has not received the order for Voltaire's works; has delivered the box to Miss Shipley and sent a letter from her to Dr. Franklin; announces the birth of a daughter.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 10; ALS, 1p.; Holker, John
    Asks for the return of the papers belonging to Messrs. Sabatie and Depononcy.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 13; L. in 3d P.; Girardot, -----
    Begs to know the first opportunity of sending to London some things which Madame has left.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 14; ALS, 2p.; Ross, John
    Encloses, for Dr. Franklin, a copy of the long budget of complaints against Mr. [Silas] Deane and others; denies the truth of these reports.
    Enclosure. Extract from the charges against Messrs. Deane, Hodge and Ross.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 15; ALS, 2p.; Petrie, S
    Wishes to know if Dr. [Edward] Bancroft has returned and if he could convey a letter to Mr. [Arthur] Lee; invites him and Dr. Franklin to dinner to meet General Bieter and M. Ventades.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 23; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Enclose a bond for a commission for a vessel "owned by A. J. Dornan and fitted in Spain under the auspices of the French Consul at Vigo"; asks for the promised letter for Mr. [John] Aitcheson; has written to Mr. [Le Ray] de Chaumont whose reproaches are injurious.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 27; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Asks to have a certified copy made, at his expense, of his amount lodged with Dr. Franklin as he has sent his only duplicate copy by the "Marquis Lafayette."
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 March 29; ALS, 3p.; Bache, Sarah
    Sent some squirrel skins by Mr. [Conrad Alexandre] Gérard [de Rayneval]; disappointed at not receiving the bust [of Dr. Franklin]; acknowledges receipt of things from her father; sent to Miss Clifton, before leaving Philadelphia, her most valuable prossessions, among them his little black trunk; the defeat of the enemy at Trenton, made it safe for her to return; the trunk is safe; the Misses Sally and Betsy Duffield have just gone home; Miss [Margaret] Shippen is married to General [Benedict] Arnold.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 1; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Sends a small bill from Madrid for acceptance.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 2; ALS, 3p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    An invitation to dinner in the country and a request for passage on the "Alliance" to return to America to serve as a volunteer.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 4; ALS, 4p.; Lorin, -----. Morlaix
    Reminds him of the service which he rendered him upon his arrival in France; asks him to use his influence to obtain for him the position of correspondent at Morlaix.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 5; ALS, 2p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Thanks him for speaking to his father; begs him to write to Captain [John Paul] Jones, and to ask his Excellency for a letter stating that the King is pleased with his services. Declines an invitation to dinner.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 7; ALS, 2p.; Lloyd, Richar Bennett
    He and his family leave soon for America; reports relating to the armament going from Brest to Canada or New York; wishes to know if there is much danger, when he arrives at Sandy Hook, of being obliged to about-ship and go to Halifax or England.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 10; ALS, 2p.; Kéralio, Agathon Guynement, chevalier de
    The alliance proposed by the Empress of Russia for the protection of the commerce of neutral nations.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 12; ALS, 2p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Sends an important package for Mr. [Jean] Holker.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 17; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Asks that Mr. [Francis] Hopkinson's things be sent by Captain [John Paul] Jones. Expects to embark soon under protection of the "Alliance"; offers his services to be useful in any way in America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 19; ALS, 2p.; Ross, John
    Asks that Dr. Franklin pay no attention to his last letter. Has obtained permission from M. [Jacques] Necker to transport the woolens, duty free.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 19; ALS, 3p.; Möeballe, Nicholas George. Middelburg
    About a Dutch vessel captured by Commodore [John Paul] Jones.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 20; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Montfort, Comte de
    Thanks him for the loan of his horse, which he sends back to him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 20; ALS, 2p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Wishes to know how much in French money is due him by Mr. [John] Bradford.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 21; ALS, 2p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Asks for the return of his papers.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 25; ALS, 2p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Sends enclosed a letter for Mr. [John Paul] Jones; gives his reasons for not returning to America; the impossibility of securing Mr. [John] Paul Jones for dinner.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 April 27; ALS, 1p.; Wharton, Joseph
    Introduces his friend Dr. John Foulke.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 3; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Thanks him for his kindness in executing Mr. [Francis] Hopkinson's order. Encloses a sheet of his letter paper and tells how to order it.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 4; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses a draft.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 6; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Wishes to know how the remainder of the clothing is to be shipped.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 9; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Still waiting for the letters for Mr. [John] Aitcheson; has been managing the European funds of the State of Maryland. Captain Samson of the "Mercury" packet arrived at Plymouth, New England, Feb. 14.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 10; ALS, 2p.; Ross, John
    Begs that Dr. Franklin will make some plan for the purchase of the "Serapis." If Dr. Franklin can devise some plan by whichs to discharge what is due him by the United States, he will buy it. The vessels here are waiting for Captain [John Paul] Jones, to sail under his protection.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 15; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Encloses bills for acceptance.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 16; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses two bills for acceptance.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 18; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses several bills drawn by Mr. [Francis] Hopkinson on the Commissioners for acceptance.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 21; ALS, 3p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    The frigate "Bonne Voitiere" is blockaded and cannot reach Ranelagh to-day.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 21; ALS, 1p.; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781
    He has given a translation to Comte de Vergennes; by order of the Minister he encloses a copy.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 23; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses six notes for acceptance drawn by Mr. Fran[cis] Hopkinson on the Commissioners at Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 27; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses two notes for acceptance, drawn by Mr. F[rancis] Hopkinson on the Commissioners at Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 29; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    His father absolutely refuses to give him the means to go to America; if he could receive the rank of Lieutenant-Colonel, he would secure the necessary funds; please renew his proposition to Mr. [John] Paul Jones.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 May 30; ALS, 1p.; de Tott, Comte
    Wishes to know about the books he asked him to get from England.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 1; ALS, 2p.; Robeson, Capt. William
    Asks him to direct some person to secure his negro boy who may have strayed towards
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 3; ALS, 1p.; Robeson, Capt. William
    The loss of the negro boy has kept him in Paris, he leaves tonight for I'Orient; should the boy be found after his departure he is to be given to Mr. [John] Adams.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 5; ALS, 1p.; Regnier, -----
    Asks for the promised letters from Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 6; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Asks that the certified copy of his account be sent by Mr. [John] Ross; wishes to know the truth of the rumor, that the French have been successful against [Admiral] Rodney.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 9; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Alexander, William
    Leaves that night in the "Diligence," asks for the packets and offers to execute any commission "an inch short of high treason." Expects to be back [from England] within three weeks.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 15; ALS, 1p.; Tardy, Gabriel.
    Encloses notes from Mr. F[ranci]s Hopkinson for acceptance.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 15; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Encloses a letter for Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 18; ALS, 2p.; Du Vivier, Pierre Simon Benjamin
    Wishes the name to be put on the medals ordered by Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 20; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Invitation to dinner.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 20; ALS, 1p.; Du Vivier, Pierre Simon Benjamin
    Did not know that the medals were to be of gold, so will bring them all in a short time.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 20; ALS, 3p.; Caslon, William
    Regrets that he cannot procure the pamphlets; sends other books by Mr. [William] Alexander. He and Mr. [James] Woodmason had lost the order for Voltaire's works, consequently the proprietors will suffer great loss. Miss Shipley will send to Dr. Franklin her father's picture as soon as she finishes it. He met their old master [James] Elphinston who is very poor.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 26; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Allaire, Peter
    Wishes to know if Mr. [John] Jay is in Paris; confirmation of the news of the taking of the Martinique fleet; other naval news.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 June 29; ALS, 2p.; Mosny, -----
    Returns the fencing outfit after making the repairs.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 July 2; ALS, 3p.; Braxton, George Jr.
    Most anxious to reach America; finds all vessels are leaving from l'Orient, so will go there.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 July 7; ALS, 1p.; De Sainte Marie, -----
    Asks that the enclosed letter be forwarded to [George] Braxton, [Jr.].
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 July 8; ALS, 2p.; Grand, Ferdinand
    Request that he search again for the bills from [Joseph] Gardoqui [Son and Co.].
  - to William Temple Franklin, [1780] July 12; ALS, 1p.; Digges, Thomas
    Mr. Burk regrets that the package for Mrs. H-----y was seized by the Margate Custom House.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 July 16; ALS, 4p.; Braxton, George Jr.
    Regrets the pleasures of Paris. The "Alliance" has sailed with the fleet. He will leave shortly in a brig which came from Philadelphia.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 July 19; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Leaves in a few days on the "Duke of Leinster" under protection of Captain [John Paul] Jones of the "Ariel"; asks for commissions for America and news of little Benjamin [Franklin] Bache.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 July 23; A.L.S 1p.; Ingersoll, Jared
    Asks that his library be forwarded to him; the French fleet arrived at Newport; Admiral [Samuel] Graves is at New York.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 July 27; ALS, 3p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Hopes he has been able to complete the Doctor's accounts, gives news of the "Hermione's" encounter with the English off New York and of the capture of " Les Etats d'Artois."
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 July 31; ALS, 2p.; Nuttle, Samuel. Havre-de-Grace
    Asks that he obtain permission for him to enter the French merchant service.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 4; ALS, 1p.; Braxton, George Jr.
    Rejoices in having such a sincere friend; any commands he will execute.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 7; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Has been made a Lieutenant-Colonel; now most desirous of returning to America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 8; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Announces the death of his cousin Jona[than] Williams; Mr. [Silas] Deane is with him and will leave for Paris in four or five days.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 14; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Mr. [Silas] Deane brings this letter and will give all the news; wishes to know Mr. [John] A[dam]s's business in Holland; please get his accounts from Mr. A[dams]. He draws on the Doctor [Franklin] for £1,520 14 s., which has been sent to Mrs. [Richard] Bache, this sum is to come from the Doctor's personal account.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 16; ALS, 3p.; Ross, John
    The delay in the sailing of Captain [John Paul] Jones is due to Mr. [Le Ray] de Chaumont who will not pay the wages and prizemoney due the crew.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 17; ALS, 1p.; Trumbull, John
    Having heard that a packet from New London was chased ashore at l'Orient and that the despatches were saved, asks that if there is a letter for him, it be sent in care of Mr. D-----.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 19; ALS, 2p.; Fox, George
    His opinion of the morals of the married women of France.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 24; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses certificates from Mr. [Francis] Hopkinson on the Commissioners.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 26; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Asks for the address of a banker, and invites him to visit him at St. Maudé.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 29; ALS, 4p.; Fox, George
    Tells of his lack of success in making love.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 29; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses a letter from Messrs. Harmar and Lewis of Philadelphia, concerning some bills. The "Cecil," belonging to Mr. DaCosta, which brought this letter, reports the success of the Americans against [Baron Wilhelm von] Knyphausen and the arrival of the French fleet. Asks his courtesy for Mrs. [William] Blake and her children of South Carolina.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Aug. 31; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses a bill which has passed through several hands without the signature of Mr. [Francis] Hopkinson. Has heard of the great capture by the Spaniards.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 1; ALS, 1p.; MacCreery, William
    Hastens to announces [Gen. Sir Henry] Clinton's defeat in Jersey by General Washington.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 8; ALS, 3p.; Ross, John
    Arrival of American vessels with despatches. The American army is increasing rapidly. Gen. [Horatio] Gates, on his march to Carolina, had collected an army of three thousand before these vessels left. The crew and officers of the vessel detained here have not yet received their wages and prize-money from M. [Le Ray] de Ch[aumont]. His management a mere fizzle and deception.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 9; ALS, 4p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Sees that one of the bills returned has already been paid, sends it back for Mr. [Ferdinand] Grand to see, so as to be able to trace the carelessness or roguery.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 14; ALS, 1p.; Le Veillard, Louis
    Returns a ticket for a ball.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 14; ALS, 2p.; Robeson, Capt. William
    Request that his portrait be sent to him by Captain Sampson.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 15; ALS, 2p.; de Perrochall, -----. Chateau du Thiel
    Asking for a passport for Mr. Esdaile, a friend.
    A.E. by W[illiam] T[emple] F[ranklin]. The passport given.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 15; A.L.S.; Fox, George
    A letter to show his knowledge of French.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 16; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Searle, James
    Thanking him for the letters and declaring his intention of dining with Dr. Franklin the next day.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 18; ALS, 1p.; Mayo, Joseph
    Encloses the letters to be forwarded to Mr. [George] Braxton, [Jr.].
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 20; ALS, 2p.; Ross, John
    Capt. [John Paul] Jones has succeeded in getting wages due 45 seamen of the "B[on] H[omme] Richard" on board the " Ariel "; but no prize-money and nothing for those gone to America; Mr. [Samuel] Wharton explains the silence of Captain Jones in this matter is due to desire not to add to his grandfather's troubles.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [1780] Sept. 26; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Mayo, Joseph
    Requests that a room he secured for him; explains that he could not dine with the Doctor [Franklin] on account of his eyes; asks that the enclosed letters be forwarded to Mr. [George] Fox.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 26; ALS, 4p.; Fox, George
    Thanks him for forwarding his packet from America; his letters contain no news of any importance. Wonders if Mr. [James] Searle has the necessary ability for his commission and what interest can Pennsylvania have separate from the other states. Gives and asks news of Various friends.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 26; ALS, 2p.; Braxton, George Jr. Grois
    Has set sail for America on the "Duke of Leinster"; hopes that Mr. [Joseph] Mayo may see the different amusements of Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 28; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Introduces Mr. Moore and returns his accounts to have them signed, examined and approved by the Doctor [Franklin].
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Sept. 30; ALS, 3p.; Chaumont, Le Ray de, fils
    Describes his life in the country.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 2; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; de Malesherbes, -----
    As requested sends three packages of seeds of plants unknown in America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 2.; ALS, 2p.; Ross, John
    Owing to adverse winds they have not been able to sail. A brig has just arrived from Philadelphia reporting the safe arrival of the "Alliance" [Capt. Pierre] Landais was put under arrest and the "Alliance" was to be offered to Captain [John] Barry.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 3.; ALS, 1p.; Mayo, Joseph
    Thanks him for his trouble in enquiring about the lodgings; also for Mr. [George] Fox and Mr. [George] Braxton, [Jr.]'s letters. Accepts his invitation to breakfast.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 11; ALS, 2p.; Collins, Thomas
    Asking him not to bother about the passports.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [1780. Oct. 11] Monday Evening.; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Deane, Silas, 1737-1789
    Asks the address of Mr. [Joseph] Mayo and Dr. [John] Foulke and for Montieu's papers.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 12; ALS, 4p.; Fox, George
    Promises to be more discreet since his letters are subject to examination; acknowledges a letter from [Joseph] Mayo; asks advice about dress; is desirous of hearing the news from America; encloses a letter for [John] Foulke; wishes to know [William] Robeson's plans.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 21; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Le Roy, Jean Baptiste
    Encloses the letters received about sauce pans; recommends Vitel; hopes Dr. Franklin's gout is better.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 24; ALS, 3p.; Kéralio, Agathon Guynement, chevalier de
    Wishes the correct news about Gen. [Horatio] Gates's defeat at Camden; the German newspapers are most uncomplimentary; if he receives an answer promptly, he will circulate the correct report.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 30; ALS, 3p.; Bache, Sarah Franklin, 1743-1808
    Besides the squirrel skins sent by Mr. [Conrad Alexandre] Gérard [de Rayneval], eighty odd were sent in a sugar box; sent also a piece of American spun silk to her father; the nuts, apples,and cotton shall be sent shortly in a twenty-gun ship; supposes he has heard about [Benedict] Arnold; gives news of her children.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Oct. 31; ALS, 3p.; Fox, George
    Great desire to know the true story of [Gen. Horatio] Gates's defeat. Wishes to know of any vessel sailing for his port as he has letters to send.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1780 Nov. 2; A.L. 2p.; Kéralio, Agathon Guynement, chevalier de